Alphonse R. Dsouza

Address Bengaluru, KA, 560094

Phone 890 480 0738

E-mail alphonse.r.dsouza@gmail.com

To utilize my strength and experience in <u>mobile application development</u> (iOS, **9 years**) for making some awesome products, for the good cause of our society. Looking for challenging projects, to be the trustworthy bridge between clients and our team and helping the team to reach greater success in a healthy working environment. Working closely with European clients onsite or from headquarter office has given a new direction to my working career.



Skills

Technology

- · Programming Languages: Swift, Objective-C
- · Web Data format: JSON, XML
- · Database: Sqlite, Mysql
- Development Tools: Xcode, Instruments, Mobile Simulators.
- · Version handling tools: Git, SVN
- Scrum master experience: 4 Months
- Trainer Role: Given iOS application development training in SAP labs, Bangalore, official coaching sessions.

Methodology

Agile (Scrum)

Contribution:

https://stackoverflow.com/users/1057814/alphonse-r-dsouza?tab=profile



Work History

WOIK IIISIOTY

Apr 2015 - Team Lead

Current

INDPRO AB, Bangalore, Karnataka

- Worked closely with software development and testing team members to design and develop robust software solutions to meet client requirements for functionality, scalability and performance.
- Established open and professional relationships with team members which helped resolve issues and conflicts quickly.
- Hired, trained and mentored staff to maximize effectiveness.

Gapstaff Manager (iPad application)

Gapstaff AB(Bangalore : Offsite) Mar 2017 to Jan 2019(Full Time)

A workforce management application for healthcare (Hospitals). Used by managers. Key features:

- Create, Edit, Delete shifts given to staff members,
- Staff members can swap swift

- · Quick view through Day and Month calendar.
- Push notification for updates.
- · Chat functionality among co-workers
- Activity log: to quickly see all activities,
- Staff members: to view their profile details, including instant chat.

https://itunes.apple.com/se/app/gapstaff-manager/id1435870667?l=en

Gapstaff Roster (iPad application)

Gapstaff AB(Bangalore: Offsite) Mar 2017 to Jan 2019(Full Time)

 Replica of Gapstaff with restricted functionalities. Used by different staffs. https://itunes.apple.com/se/app/gapstaff-roster/id1435865616?l=en

iBac Consumer (iPhone application)

Alcosystems Sweden AB(Bangalore : Offsite)

Apr 2017 to Jun 2017 (Full Time)

Alcohol level detection in their blood or evaluate their sobriety after consuming alcohol via bluetooth iBAC device .

Key challege:

 To interact with BLE Device named iBac from mobile app. https://itunes.apple.com/sg/app/ibac-consumer/id639771617?mt=8

Apr 2012 - Senior Software Engineer

Current

INDPRO AB, Bangalore, Karnataka

- Worked with project managers, developers, quality assurance and customers to resolve technical issues.
- Estimated work hours and tracked progress using Agile/SCRUM methodology.
- Reviewed code and corrected errors.

cTimeSheet (iPhone application)

Exicom AB(Bangalore : Offsite) Aug 2011 to Jan 2017(Full Time)

An app for time reporting on mobile devices. Monitoring of projects and activities. Responsibilities/role :

- Real time sync of time report details between client and the server database,
- Proper caching of companies data coming from web service,
- Displaying huge details in table view in week and search screen,
- Displaying calendar and pop-ups on its days,
- Supporting multitasking and offline time report sync management.

URL: http://itunes.apple.com/in/app/ctimesheet/id464053269?mt=8

cManager (Universal Application)

Exicom AB(Bangalore : Offsite)
Jul 2013 to Jan 2017(Full Time)

Collects the entire process for time reporting. The supervisor can now easily keep updated and continuously attest time reports and see who has not reported. Key challenges: -

- App supporting both iPhone and iPad screens.
- Customized grid screen for showing reports per month/week.

URL: https://itunes.apple.com/in/app/cmanager-for-copernicus-mobile/id785389873? mt=8

Jul 2010 - Software Engineer

Mar 2012 INDPRO AB. Ba

INDPRO AB, Bangalore, KARNATAKA

CricPredict

AdeptPros LLC(Offsite)

Jan 2011 to Feb 2011 (Full Time)

User can predict winner of the cricket matches and can win virtual money. Responsibilities/role:

- Track prediction history, JSON parsing to list top scorer and respective points and prediction points table.
- Inviting through Facebook, Twitter and Email.

URL: https://www.148apps.com/app/421119606/

CricPredictPro

AdeptPros LLC(Offsite)

Jan 2011 to Feb 2011 (Full Time)

Pro version of CricPredict

URL: https://www.148apps.com/app/421605192/

Nixon Catalog (iPad Application)

Nixon(Offsite)

Oct 2010 to Feb 2011 (Full Time)

Allows customers to buy products and products can be viewed, bookmark etc. using this pdf reader.

Responsibilities/role:

- Rendering the downloaded pdf with limitless pages.
- Slide animation of pdf pages to read next pages.
- · Easy readability with bottom thumbnail slider and
- Pdf zooming facility.

Education

2010 Bachelor of Engineering, K.L.E.C.E.T.

Computer Science, Belgaum

2006 Pre-University, Science, Kendriya Vidyalaya, CBSE Board

PCMB, Belgaum

2004 10th Grade , Kendriya Vidyalaya, CBSE Board

Belgaum

Languages

English (Proficient) Hindi (Expert) Konkani (Proficient)

Hobbies

- · Loves all outdoor and indoor games,
- Travelling, trekking etc.